{"tossups": [{"question": "According to one story, after this thinker suffered a mental breakdown, he attempted to save a horse from a flogging by wrapping his arms around it. Walter Kaufman wrote about this thinker in a book that assigned him the titles of \"philosopher,\" \"psychologist,\" and \"antichrist.\" One work by this thinker begins with the phrase \"Suppose truth is a woman --  what then?\" This thinker included (*) self-praising sections like \"Why I write such good books\" and \"Why I am so Wise\" in his autobiography Ecce Homo. This thinker described the idea of \u00dcbermensch in a book where the title prophet sometimes returns to solitude in the mountains. This thinker wrote Beyond Good and Evil and Thus Spoke Zarathustra. For 10 points, name this German philosopher who proclaimed \"God is dead.\"", "answer": "Friedrich Nietzsche", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "category": "Philosophy"}, {"question": "This group responded, \"Fortresses will not detain us, nor armies stop us\" when asked to surrender. In that event, heads of envoys from Hulagu were hung on the gate of Bab Zuweila by these people. These people fought a battle against forces led by Kitbagu at a place also known as \"Goliath's spring.\" After defeating the Safavid empire at the Battle of Chaldiran, Selim I annexed this group. This group was founded when (*) Turanshah of the Ayyubid dynasty was overthrown. One leader of this group, Qutuz, stopped a Mongol expansion at the Battle of Ain Jalut along with this group's general Baibars. This group, which was located to the south of the Ottomans, was conquered in a 1516 war. For 10 points, name this group of Islamic slave soldiers who ruled a namesake sultanate in modern-day Egypt.", "answer": "Mamluks [accept Mamluk Sultanate]", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "One review described the prose of this novel as \"facile sensuality\" with \"no theme, no message, no thought.\" This novel states that \"no matter how far a person can go the horizon is still way beyond you,\" before later describing how one character had been there and come back. Nanny tells the protagonist of this novel that certain people are like mules, leading her to later feel empathy for a mule being teased. The protagonist of this novel compares her sexuality to a blossoming (*) pear tree before kissing Johnny Taylor. That character in this novel narrates her story to her friend Pheoby. A rabid dog bites one character in this novel during a hurricane, forcing the protagonist to shoot him. That man, who is her third husband after Logan Killicks and Jody Starks, is Tea Cake. For 10 points, name this novel about Janie Crawford Written by Zora Neale Hurston.", "answer": "Their Eyes Were Watching God", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This period is home to the earliest records of the secondary palate that divides the nasal and oral cavities. This period's Guadalupian epoch was named for discoveries in the Guadalupe mountains. Synapsids, such as the Dimetrodon, were dominant land animals during this period. Volcanic eruptions that formed the Siberian Traps may have caused one event during this period. (*) Panthalassa, a superocean that primarily existed during this period, surrounded the supercontinent Pangea. This period's namesake extinction, often known as the \"great dying,\" was the largest extinction event in Earth's history. For 10 points, name this last geological period of the Paleozoic that preceded the Triassic.", "answer": "Permian period", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "A controversial pericope in this book mentions one figure writing something on the ground, leading to everyone except one woman leaving. One figure contrasts the manna consumed by the Israelites to the \"bread of life\" in a discourse in this book. In this book, a figure rubs clay on the eyes of a man in order to cure his blindness. A disputed comma in this book is a direct reference to the Trinity. One figure in this book, who also states \"I am\" at least seven times, commands that the one (*) \"without sin\" should be the first to stone an adulterous woman. This gospel says that it is based on \"the disciple whom Jesus loved.\" In the first of seven signs that appear in this gospel, a man turns water into wine at a wedding at Cana. The line \"In the beginning was the Word\" opens this gospel. For 10 points, name this last of the four gospels that follows Matthew, Mark, and Luke.", "answer": "the Gospel of John [or the Gospel According to John; accept the Book of John]", "subcategory": "Religion", "category": "Religion"}, {"question": "In the presence of pentane, dichloromethane, and this compound, O-methyl oximes and carbonyls are reacted in the Griesbaum reaction. This compound is produced by the dielectric barrier discharge method. NOx compounds catalyze the breakdown of this compound. A Criegee intermediate is formed when this compound reacts with alkenes, producing ketones or aldehydes. This compound is photochemically regenerated in the Chapman cycle. Exposing (*) rubber to this compound can result in cracking. The concentration of this compound is measured in Dobson units. The Montreal Protocol in 1987 was aimed at stopping the breakdown of this naturally occurring compound by limiting the use of chlorofluorocarbons. For 10 points, name this triatomic gas that absorbs most of the harmful UV light in the stratosphere.", "answer": "ozone [accept O3]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "A series by this artist consists of 10 works featuring scenes of different types of fishing and is titled Oceans of Wisdom. This artist also depicted \"feminine\" and \"masculine\" versions of the same, title phenomenon. In another work by this artist, an elderly man is depicted making a barrel in the title location. This artist is said to have painted falling maple leaves by chasing a chicken whose feet were dipped in red paint. A diver is enveloped by two (*) octopi in an erotic work by this artist, The Dream of the Fisherman's Wife. The rising sun causes a landmark in this artist's Fine Wind, Clear Morning to appear red. Three boats are threatened by the title phenomenon in a woodblock print by this artist. For 10 points, name this Japanese artist whose Great Wave off Kanagawa is included in his collection Thirty-Six Views of Mount Fuji.", "answer": "Katsushika Hokusai", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "In this story, a character declares that he will not \"play ... the part that Paris played\" after comparing three women to the Three Graces. In this story, Lily is handed a coin because it is around Christmas after being asked about marriage. In this story, guests begin to sing \"For they are jolly good fellows.\" While waltzing, this story's protagonist is interrogated about his lack of nationalism by Miss (*) Ivors. At the end of this story, the protagonist muses on the impermanence of life as he hears \"snow falling faintly through the universe.\" Characters in this story overhear the tenor Bartell D'Arcy singing \"The Lass of Aughrim\" at a ball hosted by the Misses Morkin. In this story, the death of the young Michael Furey is recounted to the protagonist by his wife Gretta. For 10 points, name this story about the Irishman Gabriel Conroy, written by James Joyce.", "answer": "\"The Dead\"", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "It's not Ulm or Austerlitz, but this city was captured after the Ulm campaign, since a large Russian army under Kutuzov was still near this city. This city was protected by a line of fortifications called the Linienwall. An invasion of this city prompted Innocent XI to create the Holy League. The July Putsch, an attempted coup in this city, resulted in the assassination of Engelbert Dollfuss. One event in this city was interrupted by the (*) Hundred Days. One siege of this city was ended when John Sobieski led a cavalry charge of 20,000 Winged Hussars. A conference in this city maintained a balance of power in the \"Concert of Europe\" by restoring Europe's borders to before the French revolution; that event was chaired by Klemens von Metternich. For 10 points, name this capital of the Austrian Empire.", "answer": "Vienna [accept Wien]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "One character in this TV show once tricked two men into thinking he was their boss using shadows, laughter, and a paper hat. During this show, one character appears to gain superhuman abilities after eating food named after his closest friend. The first episode of this show is titled \"What a Night for a Knight.\" In this show, it is revealed that Dr. Jekyll was stealing jewels in disguise as the (*) Ghost of Hyde. Characters on this show often say, \"I'd have gotten away with it too, if it weren't for those kids.\" The real name of one character in this show is Norville Rogers, and he often shouts \"Zoinks!.\" For 10 points, name this show home to the Mystery Machine and the characters Shaggy and the title Great Dane.", "answer": "Scooby-Doo [accept Scooby-Doo, Where are You!]", "subcategory": "Trash", "category": "Trash"}, {"question": "In the work in which these characters appear, they are told \"I will be satisfied: deny me this, And an eternal curse fall on you.\" After one of these characters discusses a sailor's wife, the others offer to help her control the winds. One man says about these characters \"Infected be the air whereon they ride\" after Lennox says he did not see them. These characters summon an (*) apparition that looks like a bloody child to tell a character that no man born of a woman can harm him, in addition to chanting \"Double, double toil and trouble.\" In the play in which these characters appear, they call the Thane of Glamis the Thane of Cawdor and tell him that he will be king and tell Banquo that his descendants will be kings. For 10 points, give the collective name for the three witches from Macbeth.", "answer": "Weird Sisters [accept the witches from Macbeth or equivalents before \"witches,\" prompt on witches or characters from Macbeth]", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This quantity is divided by e squared in the formula for the von Klitzing constant, which quantizes resistance in the quantum Hall effect. Taking the limit as this quantity goes to zero gives classical physics. The elementary charge squared divided by the speed of light times this quantity equals the fine structure constant in CGS units. The Compton wavelength equals this quantity divided by mc. Dividing this quantity by (*) 2pi gives its \"reduced form,\" which is symbolized by a bar. The energy of a photon equals this constant times frequency. This constant approximately equals 6.626 times 10 to the negative 34. The namesake of this constant proposed that light was made up of \"quanta.\" For 10 points, name this constant symbolized h that is named after the formulator of quantum theory.", "answer": "Planck's constant [prompt on h before mentioned; do not accept or prompt on \"reduced Planck constant\" or \"h-bar\"]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "One president of this country drank orange juice on television to protest what he viewed as the unproductiveness of fasting. This country blockaded a base at Bizerte controlled by its colonial power, which this country lost but later got the base back. This country's Code of Personal Status, which was supported by the Neo-Destour party, gave women rights. The Popular Front in this country accused the political party Ennahda of killing two of its leaders. This country's president Habib (*) Bourguiba was deposed in a coup led by its next president, Zine El Abidine Ben Ali, who was himself deposed in a revolution sometimes called the Jasmine Revolution. The vendor Mohamed Bouazizi set himself on fire in this country, sparking its revolution as well as the Arab Spring. For 10 points, name this North African country which contains the ruins of Carthage, and borders both Algeria and Libya.", "answer": "Republic of Tunisia [accept R\u00e9publique tunisienne; accept al-jumh\u016br\u012byah at-T\u016bnis\u012byah]"}, {"question": "A politician from this state said \"I hope Q is real, because it only means America is getting stronger and better.\" One politician from this state tweeted \"The easiest way to make the Delta variant go away is to turn off CNN. And vote Republican.\" That politician from this state was accused of helping rioters by tweeting Pelosi's location during the Jan. 6 riot. One politician from this state gained fame for owning a restaurant called (*) Shooters Grill where servers openly carried guns. This state's politician Scott Tipton was primaried by a politician who failed to disclose her husband's gas consulting and repeatedly set off Capitol metal detectors. That politician confronted Beto O'Rourke about gun control at a rally in this state's city of Aurora. For 10 points, name this state home to John Hickenlooper, Michael Bennet, and Lauren Boebert.", "answer": "Colorado", "subcategory": "Current Events", "category": "Current Events"}, {"question": "Composers from this country founded the Society for Private Musical Performances. The Fires of London group was originally founded by Peter Davies and Harrison Birtwistle to play a piece from this country. An ensemble named for a piece from this country consists of piano, violin, cello, clarinet, flute, and voice. Louis Krasner premiered a violin concerto from this country dedicated (*) \"to the memory of an angel.\" The Klangfarbenmelodie techniques were invented by a theorist from this country. A supposedly nonexistent inverted ninth chord was used in a string sextet from this country inspired by a Richard Dehmel poem. A composer from this country wrote the operas Wozzeck and Lulu. For 10 points, name this country, home to twelve-tone serialists like Arnold Schoenberg.", "answer": "Austria", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "During one election, this person used the Morgan-Ryan-Belmont resolution to prevent Speaker of the House Champ Clark from receiving the presidential nomination. Both Arthur Sewall and Thomas Watson were vice presidential nominees for this person in one election. After the sinking of the RMS Lusitania, this person resigned as Woodrow Wilson's Secretary of (*) State. Mark Hanna helped one opponent of this person run a successful \"front porch\" campaign from his home in Canton, Ohio. This person lost the 1912 presidential election to William Howard Taft. At one speech at the DNC, this man said \"you shall not crucify mankind upon\" the namesake object in support of \"Free Silver.\" For 10 points, name this Nebraska Populist who ran for president against William Mckinley in 1896 and gave the \"Cross of Gold\" speech.", "answer": "William Jennings Bryan", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This author asks \"What merchant's ships have my sighs drowned?\" in a poem that begins with the admonition \"For God's sake hold your tongue and let me love.\" \"The Heresy of Paraphrase\" is included in a Cleanth Brooks book titled for a phrase from this poet's \"The Canonization,\" The Well-Wrought Urn. In one poem, this author likens himself to \"an usurp'd town to another due.\" In that poem, this author begs for (*) God to \"break, blow, burn, and make me new\" and notes that he is never \"chaste, except you ravish me.\" One poem by this author claims that \"Poppy or charms can make us sleep as well\" as the title being, who is \"slave to Fate, Chance, kings, and desperate men.\" For 10 points, name this English Metaphysical poet of nineteen Holy Sonnets, including \"Death, be not proud....\" --------------------------------------------------------------------------------", "answer": "John Donne --------------------------------------------------------------------------------", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "One song by this artist ends with describing but not naming a snake after repeating that \"In the beginning,\" the title action happened. In another song by this artist, the singer asks for the presence of his love rather than any European gift before asking for the title boots. Judas Iscariot and various wars are mentioned in a song by this artist of \"Man Gave Names to All the Animals\" and \"Boots of Spanish Leather\" that asks \"Was God on our side?\"; this artist also references Judas in his song (*) \"Masters of War.\" The film Don't Look Back, about this artist, starts by displaying lyrics for his song \"Subterranean Homesick Blues.\" This artist was apocryphally booed for using an electric guitar at the 1965 Newport festival, where he performed his song \"Like a Rolling Stone.\" For 10 points, name this Nobel Prize winning singer-songwriter who wrote the song \"Blowin' in the Wind.\"", "answer": "Bob Dylan [accept Robert Allen Zimmerman]", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This figure was given hellebore by Antikyreos. Prodicus told one story about this figure where he is visited by personifications of vice and virtue at a crossroads. This figure's companion Hylas was drowned by naiads resulting in this figure being left in Mysia. Galanthis was turned into a weasel for helping in the (*) birth of this figure. This figure killed his music teacher Linus by hitting him on the head with a lyre in one story. This hero's weapons, which were needed by the Greeks to win the Trojan War, were given to Philoctetes. This son of Alcmene was originally named Alcides or Alcaeus but was renamed after strangling snakes sent by Hera. Eurystheus instructed this hero to kill Geryon, the Nemean Lion, and the Lernaean Hydra. For 10 points, name this Greco-Roman hero who completed 12 labors.", "answer": "Heracles [accept Hercules; accept Alcides or Alcaeus before mention]", "subcategory": "Mythology", "category": "Mythology"}, {"question": "Note to moderator: read the answerline carefully. One type of this process can be classified into three forms called arrhenotoky, thelytoky, and deuterotoky. Organisms that primarily undergo this process can experience Muller's ratchet, which explains its rarity. Some plants can undergo this process by forming stolons. One form of this process that occurs in plants is (*) apomixis. Charles Bonnet first observed one type of this process in aphids. Komodo dragons undergo parthenogenesis, one type of this process. Bacteria undergo a type of this process called binary fission. This kind of reproduction occurs when an organism does not undergo meiosis. For 10 points, name this kind of reproduction in which an organism creates offspring by itself.", "answer": "asexual reproduction [accept asexual after \"reproduction\"; accept parthenogenesis until mentioned; accept cloning; prompt on reproduction; do not accept or prompt on \"sexual reproduction\" or \"mating\" or \"growth\"]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}], "bonuses": []}